Guide to the Faculty of Yale College Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Faculty of Yale College records
1751-1994
RU 541
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(13 boxes)
The records consist of memoranda and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Faculty of Yale College. Included are minutes from meetings of the faculty and executive committee, committee reports, attendance books, committee membership lists, and financial papers.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-C (YRG 9-C), Records of Yale College officers and faculty.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Faculty of Yale College. Included are minutes from meetings of the faculty and executive committee, committee reports, attendance books, committee membership lists, and financial papers.
Existence and Location of Copies
Judgments of the President and Tutors of Yale College (1751-1768), is available on microfilm (1 reel, 35mm) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM17.
Faculty minutes (1807-1957) is available on microfilm (1,205 frames on 2 reels, 35mm), from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM217.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Faculty; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Administration; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty
- Judgments of the President and Tutors of Yale College, 1751-1768; Accession 1932-A-005
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Judgments of the President and Tutors of Yale College (1751-1768), is available on microfilm (1 reel, 35mm) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM17.
  - Yale University Faculty Judgments: Judgments of the President and Tutors of Yale College, 1973-1768, in individual cases of student misconduct and scholastic performance., 1751-1768 (Box 1)
- Academic and meeting records of the Yale College faculty, 1889-1891; Accession 1933-A-004
  - Yale College List of Conditions, 1889-1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Warnings for Scholarship, Faculty Meetings, 1890-1891 (Box 1)
  - Absences from examinations (Box 1)
- Records of the Yale College faculty, 1807-1857; Accession 1934-A-004
  - Faculty records, minutes and appointment lists
    - 1807-1817 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1817-1851 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1850-1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1862-1883 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1883-1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1829-1857 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Minutes of the Yale College faculty, 1976; Accession 1977-A-010
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Yale College faculty meeting minutes, 1976 April 29 (Box 1)
- Records of the Yale College faculty, 1904-1971; Accession 1978-A-009
  - Faculty meetings: minutes; Executive Committee: minutes, 1919-1957, 1926-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty committee reports, 1904-1922 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Faculty committee reports, 1921-1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Faculty committee reports, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Faculty committee reports, 1950-1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Faculty committee reports, 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Faculty committee reports, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty and Committee meetings: attendance books, 1936-1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Committee membership lists, 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Committee membership lists, 1959-1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Improving Instruction: reports (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Fund for Justice: cashbook, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Reports and correspondence of the Yale College faculty, 1762-1897; Accession 1979-A-015
  - Reports, minutes, note concerning academical dept., esp. changes in curriculum and sanitary conditions in dormitories, 1762-1885 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Faculty and turtors' correspondence, 1776-1871 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence concerning student discipline and letters addressed to individual faculty members, 1820-1884 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student appointments, 1836-1851 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1849-1897 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes of the Yale College faculty, 1983-1985; Accession 1985-A-017
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021.
  - Yale College faculty meeting minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
- Yale College Faculty meeting minutes, 1981-1994; Accession 2001-A-064
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2030.
  - Yale College faculty meeting minutes, 1981-1994 (Box 1)